Deep Water is a documentary, adventure, drama film directed by Jerry Rothwell.
DEEP WATER is the stunning true story of the fateful voyage of Donald Crowhurst, an amateur yachtsman who enters
the most daring nautical challenge ever – the very first solo, non-stop, round-the-world boat race.
Narrator (voice), played by Tilda Swinton.
Donald Crowhurst (voice), played by Simon Russell Beale.
Bernard Moitessier (voice), played by Jean Badin.
Self (archive footage), played by Donald Crowhurst.
Self, played by Clare Crowhurst.
Self, played by Simon Crowhurst.
Deep Water is a 2006 British documentary film directed by Jerry Rothwell and Louise
Osmond, and produced by Al Morrow, Jonny Persey and John Smithson.
It is based on the true story of British businessman and amateur sailor Donald Crowhurst, as he participated in the Sunday
Times Golden Globe Race, a single-handed, round-the-world yacht race held in 1968–69, during which he disappeared.
The film reconstructs Crowhurst's voyage from his own audio tapes and
cine film, interwoven with archival footage and interviews.
The film explores themes of boat, biography, based on
true story, woman director, yachtsman.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.